

Evgeniy Toropitsyn

Front-end React developer

https://www.linkedin.com/in/evgeniy-toropitsyn
Toropitsynevgeniy@gmail.com
+420 773942231
Prague

Profile

Front-end developer with experience in React and Node.js (JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, Material UI, Bootstrap, Anolis, Figma, Express, MongoDB, Git, Jira, Postman). Highly motivated to learn new skills and technologies. Enthusiastic about creating new products and searching for non-standard solutions. Hands-on experience with corporate software development and web application testing. A team player with extensive experience working in international teams on large European projects. Six years of experience in new product development (drugs and pharmaceutical devices). Wide knowledge in other non-IT areas that can be useful in the development of new products.

Employment history

Software Tester; Trainee Front-end developer, Trask a.s., Prague, Czech Rep. April 2023 – present

- Software application testing (Jira)
- Work shift planner software development (front-end: React, TS)

Data analyst, Contipro a.s., Czech Republic

February 2022 – August 2022 (6 months)

 Development of models for the rheological data evaluation and subsequent storage in the MongoDB database (Trios, Excel, JavaScript, NodeJS (Express), MongoDB)

Researcher, Contipro a.s., Czech Republic

August 2016 – August 2022 (6 years)

Research and development of new products (medical devices)

Web development projects

https://plannerevtor.herokuapp.com

Web application for planning events and sharing with other participants

• Front-end: React

• Back-end: Node.is, Express

• Database: MongoDB

• Server:

front-end: Heroku, back-end: Heroku • GitHub:

github.com/EvTor/Planner EvTor

• Testing accounts:

Tester1@mail.com (password: 1111) Tester2@mail.com (password: 1111) Tester3@mail.com (password: 1111)

 Main functions: creating groups (complete CRUD), creating events (complete CRUD), searching users by email, sharing events with your groups, ability to accept / decline invitations and many others

<u>https://github.com/EvTor/</u>: Task_Prediction (JavaScript, Node, Express; REST API uses SARIMA model to predict sales), web pages: CalendarJS, ProjectJS_rekvalifikace

Education

ITnetwork s.r.o. Retraining course JavaScript web development (Educational program accredited by MEYS of the Czech Republic) August 2022 – December 2022

The course included:

- JavaScript basics
- Object-oriented programming in JavaScript
- Debugging in JS
- Node.js and Express basics
- UML and design patterns
- GIT and testing
- Modern web design
- Bootstrap

The University of Chemistry and Technology, Prague. Master's degree

September 2014 – June 2016

Study programme: Synthesis and manufacture of pharmaceuticals

Abilities, knowledge and skills

Technical skills

- React, Next
- Node.is
- JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript
- HTML 5, CSS 3
- UML, Fiama
- MaterialUI, Bootstrap, Anolis, Adaptability xstyled
- **Express**
- MongoDB
- Git
- Jira
- Postman

Personal skills

- Critical thinking analytical and analysis of the problem
- Strong organizational skills
- Creativity
- Willingness to learn new things
- Motivation

Professional skills

- Hands-on experience with corporate software development
- Writing documentation, evaluation end presentation of project results
- Design and planning of new product development projects
- Coordination of work between working groups
- Training of new employees
- Working in international teams on large European projects (N2B, DRIVE, AMCARE)

Languages

- Czech: Advanced (C1)
- English: Intermediate (B2)
- French: Elementary (A2)
- Russian: Advanced (C1)